Official name

Jan Pavle Posma

**US** status

H-1B visa

Languages

Dutch (native), English (IELTS score 8.0)

Phone number +1 (415) 881-0006 E-mail address j@npaulpos.ma Website

janpaulposma.nl

This is a shortened version. Find the full interactive document online at janpaulposma.nl/cv.

# **Curriculum Vitae: Jan Paul Posma**

Oxford-graduated computer scientist with a broad range of interests. Current focus: revitalising democracy. I've written production code in 15 languages, taught programming and engineering for 8 years, made 3 legacy code bases maintainable again, wrote ~6000 lines of pure compiler code to make new UIs possible, and once used 25 wine glasses in a project for MTV.

## Professional experience

### Brigade (web developer)

2015 - present

I'm working on the web application, where I mainly focus on features for **customer growth**; several of my proposals and implementations have significantly increased our rate of acquisition. I introduced **engineering practices** that keep the complexity of our application contained, and I created a system for managing, visualising, and testing **analytics events** and **experiments**.

Versal (web developer) 2013 – 2015

At **Versal** I worked on the core product: an **authoring tool for interactive courses**, built from the belief that we are vastly underutilising the computer's potential in education. Based on lessons learned, I co-authored a new API for "gadgets" — building blocks of courses, such as videos, quizzes, simulations, games, and so on. We launched our development platform with this new API, and it was well received by gadget developers (much of the API has been **released as open source**). I also **mentored** several junior engineers, **spoke at industry events**, and advised on **systems architecture and product design**.

#### Factlink (web developer)

2012 - 2014

At **Factlink** we built an open source tool for **curbing misinformation** on the web. I worked on getting traction and applying good engineering practices. In 2015 I adapted some of the code for the open source project **Annotator.js**.

### Wikimedia Foundation (web developer)

2011

I have worked for **Wikimedia Foundation** in the **features team**, developing new tools for **Wikipedia**, sister projects, and other wikis running the open source **MediaWiki** software. For the most time I worked on **WikiLove**, a feature that got major **media coverage**.

#### WorldTicketShop (web developer)

2009 – 2010

At **WorldTicketShop** I was one of the first hires to work on the new **marketplace**. Although working only part-time for most of the time, I built large parts of the **critical infrastructure** of the site, made sure the **transition** between the old and the new site went well, did some of the dynamic parts of the **front-end** and was in charge of the **performance**.

### Cantouch (multitouch developer intern)

summer of 2009

At **Cantouch** I worked on the Cube, which is a large **multi-touch table** supporting many touches at the same time, which made it really interesting to build applications for this device. I built two **promotional applications** for Technische Unie, a Dutch wholesale business.

#### Education

### MSc in Computer Science, University of Oxford

2011 – 2012

My final project was **JavaScript dares**, an **interactive online programming course** aimed at high school students. It featured a carefully crafted set of **puzzles** based on the LOGO turtle and Karel the Robot, and a custom subset implementation of Javascript called **js--** to make **time-travel debugging and visualisation of execution** possible.

#### BSc in Computing Science (cum laude), University of Groningen

2008 - 2011

For my bachelor thesis I have researched new ways of **editing wikis** such as **Wikipedia**. In October 2010 I presented preliminary results at the MediaWiki Hack-A-Ton in Washington D.C. on invitation of the **Wikimedia Foundation**. In 2011 development continued in close collaboration with developers of **GRNET**, a Greek government-funded research institute. The results of this work were presented at a gathering in Berlin in May 2011. The final thesis received a mark of **9.5** (out of 10).

#### Willem Lodewijk Gymnasium, Groningen

2002 - 2008

My graduation project was PimpMyBike, an electronic circuit placed in the wheel of a bike, which displays an image when driving.

### Experience, prizes, and awards

For the **Generation Citizen Civic Tech Challenge 2015** a fellow programmer and I teamed up with a group that advocates for a lower voting age. In one day we put together a **website** that tells San Francisco voters why lowering the voting age is a good idea, and concrete steps they can take to help. Our team won the competition's **Civic Alignment Prize**.

#### **Visualising Program Execution**

2015

Based on my work on **jsdares** and research into debugging tools, I developed prototypes for new ways of **gathering and visualising execution traces** of programs. I presented my findings at a few conferences: ForwardJS, OSCON, and Strange Loop. After that, I released the **final prototype**, which I actually used in our production codebase at Brigade.

#### **λ Lessons** (With Steve Krouse)

2014

In this hackathon hosted by Y Combinator we created  $\lambda$  Lessons, an open source Haskell course. For this we implemented a custom Haskell parser and interactive visualisation of functional expansion and reduction. Our work generated significant interest in the web development and functional programming community — even a spin-off was made, the very entertaining  $\lambda$  Bubble Pop.

#### Science Center North (volunteer)

2008 - 2011

As an unpaid volunteer, I worked at **SCN** with children (age 10–18) on **electronics** and **programming** projects. I taught about soldering, (embedded) programming, and the drawing of schematics and circuit boards. We built **oscilloscope games**, **robots**, **aquarium discos**, and **alarm clocks** that played the Super Mario and Tetris themes.

### Various open source projects

I developed parts of **usbpicprog**, an open source, open hardware project, consisting of a **hardware device** and a piece of **cross-platform C++ software**.

I founded **OpenLaserFrag**, an open source, open hardware **laser-tag game**. I built the original hardware and software, which is now being built on without my involvement.

Other activities include **photography**, playing the **piano**, and the occasional **skiing** and **sailing**. I enjoy building **interesting things**, such as a **computer in a briefcase**, **balloon molecules**, **self-enumerating pangrams**, or a **voice-controlled apartment**. For more information on my personal interests, please visit my website: **janpaulposma.nl**.